Guide to John P. Wood Collection
Erie Canal Museum
John P. Wood Collection
1851 - 1908
Correspondence between John P. Wood and various family members and business associates. Wood and his sons, Able and Abram, ran a shipping business on the Erie Canal.
2 boxes
Wood, John P.
Erie Canal Museum 318 Erie Boulevard East Syracuse, NY 13202
The Collection is open for research use.
John P. Wood and his sons, Able J. Wood and Abram P. Wood, ran a business shipping items on the Erie Canal.
Erie Canal (N.Y.); Toles, Perry E.; Wood, Able J.; Wood, Abram P.; Mann, Curtis; Hoag, Harry
Personal and business correspondence of John P. Wood, who ran a shipping business on the Erie Canal. The bulk of the letters are between John P. Wood and his son, Able J. Wood, in Buffalo, NY. Perry E. Toles, Curtis Mann, and Harry Hoag also figure prominently in business correspondence.
- Correspondence
  - Correspondence 1851
    - Correspondence, 1851, October 30, 1851; Includes item 66.15.257 (Box 1, Folder Wood Collection--Correspondence 1851)
  - Correspondence 1852
    - Correspondence, 1852, October 8, 1852; Includes item 66.15.305 (Box 1, Folder Wood Collection--Correspondence, 1852)
  - Correspondence 1856
    - Correspondence, 1856, April, 1856 - October, 1856; Includes items 66.15.369, 66.15.251 (Box 1, Folder Wood Collection--Correspondence, 1856)
  - Correspondence 1857
    - Correspondence, 1857, April, 1857 - October, 1857; Includes items 66.15.252, 66.15.628, 66.15.256, 66.15.250, 66.15.248, 66.15.255, 66.15.247, 66.15.253, 66.15.249, 66.15.254 (Box 1, Folder Wood Collection--Correspondence, 1857)
  - Correspondence 1858
    - Correspondence, 1858, Includes item 66.15.154 (Box 1, Folder Wood Collection--Correspondence, 1858)
    - Correspondence, January 1858, Includes items 66.15.235, 66.15.145, 66.15.236, 66.15.226, 66.15.146, 66.15.182 (Box 1, Folder Wood Collection--Correspondence, January 1858)
    - Correspondence, February & March 1858, February, 1858 - March, 1858; Includes items 66.15.163, 66.15.144, 66.15.115, 66.15.143, 66.15.142, 66.15.141, 66.15.140, 66.15.147, 66.15.355 (Box 1, Folder Wood Collection--Correspondence, February & March 1858)
    - Correspondence, April 1858, Includes items 66.15.59, 66.15.292, 66.15.308, 66.15.354, 66.15.356-.368, 66.15.370-.375 (Box 1, Folder Wood Collection--Correspondence, April 1858)
    - Correspondence, May 1858, Includes items 66.15.61, 66.15.65, 66.15.446, 66.15.448, 66.15.476, 66.15.479, 66.15.518-.521, 66.15.523-.527, 66.15.544-.547, 66.15.558-.559, 66.15.611-.612 (Box 1, Folder Wood Collection--Correspondence, May 1858)
    - Correspondence, June 1858, Includes items 66.15.55, 66.15.289-.291, 66.15.293-.294, 66.15.297-.303, 66.15.497, 66.15.513-.517 (Box 1, Folder Wood Collection--Correspondence, June 1858)
    - Correspondence, July 1858, Includes items 66.15.114, 66.15.295, 66.15.475, 66.15.500, 66.15.560 (Box 1, Folder Wood Collection--Correspondence, July 1858)
    - Correspondence, August 1858, Includes items 66.15.56, 66.15.60, 66.15.113, 66.15.213, 66.15.222, 66.15.443, 66.15.454-.456, 66.15.459-.462, 66.15.464-.466, 66.15.470-.472, 66.15.479, 66.15.499, 66.15.562-.568, 66.15.613-.619 (Box 1, Folder Wood Collection--Correspondence, August 1858)
    - Correspondence, September 1858, Includes items 66.15.102-.105, 66.15.137-.138, 66.15.158, 66.15.189, 66.15.211, 66.15.223, 66.15.245, 66.15.296, 66.15.442, 66.15.498, 66.15.501-.505, 66.15.555 (Box 1, Folder Wood Collection--Correspondence, September 1858)
    - Correspondence, October 1858, Includes items 66.15.51, 66.15.53, 66.15.282-.283, 66.15.285-.287, 66.15.289, 66.15.304, 66.15.307, 66.15.519, 66.15.529-.531, 66.15.533-.538, 66.15.540, 66.15.543, 66.15.552-.554, 66.15.556-.557, 66.15.570-.578, 66.15.580-.584, 66.15.620, 66.15.629-.630 (Box 1, Folder Wood Collection--Correspondence, October 1858)
    - Correspondence, November 1858, Includes items 66.15.52, 66.15.54, 66.15.184, 66.15.198, 66.15.207, 66.15.215-.216, 66.15.333, 66.15.412-.418, 66.15.445, 66.15.480, 66.15.483, 66.15.541-.542, 66.15.548-.549, 66.15.551, 66.15.559, 66.15.585-.587, 66.15.621-.623 (Box 1, Folder Wood Collection--Correspondence, November 1858)
    - Correspondence, December 1858, Includes items 66.15.196, 66.15.214, 66.15.231, 66.15.241-.242, 66.15.244, 66.15.320-.332, 66.15.335-.341, 66.15.450-.451, 66.15.458, 66.15.467 (Box 1, Folder Wood Collection--Correspondence, December 1858)
  - Correspondence 1859
    - Correspondence, January 1859, Includes items 66.15.157, 66.15.181, 66.15.224-.225, 66.15.227-.230, 66.15.232-.234, 66.15.237-.240, 66.15.243 (Box 1, Folder Wood Collection--Correspondence, January 1859)
    - Correspondence, February 1859, Includes items 66.15.50, 66.15.173-.179, 66.15.212, 66.15.469, 66.15.506-.507, 66.15.588-.590 (Box 1, Folder Wood Collection--Correspondence, February 1859)
    - Correspondence, March 1859, Includes items 66.15.48-.49, 66.15.136, 66.15.172, 66.15.180, 66.15.591-.605, 66.15.624-.627 (Box 1, Folder Wood Collection--Correspondence, March 1859)
    - Correspondence, April 1859, Includes items 66.15.122-.135, 66.15.161-.162, 66.15.219-.221 (Box 1, Folder Wood Collection--Correspondence, April 1859)
    - Correspondence, May 1859, Includes items 66.15.45, 66.15.100, 66.15.119, 66.15.209, 66.15.258-.281, 66.15.606 (Box 1, Folder Wood Collection--Correspondence, May 1859)
    - Correspondence, June 1859, Includes items 66.15.47, 66.15.69 (Box 1, Folder Wood Collection--Correspondence, June 1859)
    - Correspondence, July 1859, Includes items 66.15.66-.68, 66.15.70-.78 (Box 1, Folder Wood Collection--Correspondence, July 1859)
    - Correspondence, August 1859, Includes item 66.15.46 (Box 1, Folder Wood Collection--Correspondence, August 1859)
    - Correspondence, September 1859, Includes items 66.15.190, 66.15.447 (Box 1, Folder Wood Collection--Correspondence, September 1859)
    - Correspondence, October 1859, Includes items 66.15.64, 66.15.116, 66.15.192-.195, 66.15.197, 66.15.199-.206, 66.15.342-.353, 66.15.435-.438, 66.15.478 (Box 1, Folder Wood Collection--Correspondence, October 1859)
    - Correspondence, December 1859, Includes item 66.15.334 (Box 1, Folder Wood Collection--Correspondence, December 1859)
  - Correspondence 1860
    - Correspondence, February 1860, Includes items 66.15.384, 66.15.386, 66.15.389, 66.15.391 (Box 2, Folder Wood Collection--Correspondence, February 1860)
    - Correspondence, March 1860, Includes items 66.15.111, 66.15.376-.383, 66.15.385, 66.15.387-.388, 66.15.390, 66.15.423, 66.15.425 (Box 2, Folder Wood Collection--Correspondence, March 1860)
    - Correspondence, April 1860, Includes items 66.15.420, 66.15.421 (Box 2, Folder Wood Collection-Correspondence, April 1860)
    - Correspondence, May 1860, Includes items 66.15.31-.32, 66.15.63, 66.15.117, 66.15.156, 66.15.419, 66.15.433-.434, 66.15.444 (Box 2, Folder Wood Collection--Correspondence, May 1860)
    - Correspondence, June 1860, Includes items 66.15.155, 66.15.217 (Box 2, Folder Wood Collection--Correspondence, June 1860)
    - Correspondence, July 1860, Includes item 66.15.151 (Box 2, Folder Wood Collection--Correspondence, July 1860)
    - Correspondence, August 1860, Includes items 66.15.30, 66.15.159-.160 (Box 2, Folder Wood Collection--Correspondence, August 1860)
    - Correspondence, September 1860, Includes items 66.15.35, 66.15.310, 66.15.311, 66.15.607 (Box 2, Folder Wood Collection--Correspondence, September 1860)
    - Correspondence, October 1860, Includes items 66.15.34, 66.15.36, 66.15.120, 66.15.309, 66.15.312-.319 (Box 2, Folder Wood Collection--Correspondence, October 1860)
    - Correspondence, November 1860, Includes items 66.15.1-.6, 66.15.37, 66.15.153, 66.15.392 (Box 2, Folder Wood Collection--Correspondence, November 1860)
    - Correspondence, December 1860, Includes items 66.15.33, 66.15.38, 66.15.101, 66.15.186 (Box 2, Folder Wood Collection--Correspondence, December 1860)
  - Correspondence, 1861
    - Correspondence, January 1861, Includes items 66.15.19, 66.15.40, 66.15.424 (Box 2, Folder Wood Collection--Correspondence, January 1861)
    - Correspondence, February 1861, Includes items 66.15.7, 66.15.9-.18, 66.15.20-.29, 66.15.39, 66.15.57, 66.15.110, 66.15.112, 66.15.150, 66.15.185, 66.15.62, 66.15.218 (Box 2, Folder Wood Collection--Correspondence, February 1861)
    - Correspondence, March 1861, Includes items 66.15.44, 66.15.79-.99, 66.15.148, 66.15.210, 66.15.394 (Box 2, Folder Wood Collection--Correspondence, March 1861)
    - Correspondence, May 1861, Includes item 66.15.422 (Box 2, Folder Wood Collection--Correspondence, May 1861)
    - Correspondence, June 1861, Includes items 66.15.42-.43, 66.15.149, 66.15.152, 66.15.171, 66.15.393, 66.15.395-.401, 66.15.404-.406, 66.15.509-.512 (Box 2, Folder Wood Collection--Correspondence, June 1861)
    - Correspondence, July 1861, Includes items 66.15.41, 66.15.8, 66.15.118, 66.15.121, 66.15.164-.170, 66.15.407, 66.15.409, 66.15.608 (Box 2, Folder Wood Collection--Correspondence, July 1861)
    - Correspondence, August 1861, Includes item 66.15.569 (Box 2, Folder Wood Collection--Correspondence, August 1861)
    - Correspondence, September 1861, Includes item 66.15.183 (Box 2, Folder Wood Collection--Correspondence, September 1861)
    - Correspondence, October 1861, Include items 66.15.106-.109, 66.15.408, 66.15.449, 66.15.484-.495, 66.15.550 (Box 2, Folder Wood Collection--Correspondence, October 1861)
    - Correspondence, November 1861, Includes items 66.15.410, 66.15.477, 66.15.481, 66.15.482, 66.15.496, 66.15.610 (Box 2, Folder Wood Collection--Correspondence, November 1861)
  - Correspondence 1862
    - Correspondence, September 1862, Includes items 66.15.432, 66.15.440 (Box 2, Folder Wood Collection--Correspondence, September 1862)
    - Correspondence, December 1862, Includes items 66.15.58, 66.15.246, 66.15.452 (Box 2, Folder Wood Collection--Correspondence, December 1862)
  - Correspondence 1863
    - Correspondence, 1863, Includes items 66.15.188, 66.15.411, 66.15.426, 66.15.429-.430 (Box 2, Folder Wood Collection--Correspondence, 1863)
  - Correspondence 1864
    - Correspondence, 1864, Includes items 66.15.187, 66.15.428, 66.15.431, 66.15.441 (Box 2, Folder Wood Collection--Correspondence, 1864)
  - Correspondence 1865
    - Correspondence, February 1865, Includes item 66.15.439 (Box 2, Folder Wood Collection--Correspondence, February 1865)
  - Correspondence 1908
    - Correspondence, February 1908, Includes item 66.15.139 (Box 2, Folder Wood Collection--Correspondence, February 1908)
  - Correspondence No Date
    - Correspondence, No Date, Includes items 66.15.186, 66.15.288, 66.15.306, 66.15.399, 66.15.403, 66.15.427, 66.15.522, 66.15.528, 66.15.609 (Box 2, Folder Wood Collection---Correspondence, No Date)